export const LEATHERWORKA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The record of early history were found on scrolls called",
A: "manuscript.",
B: "parchment.",
C: "hieroglyphics.",
D: "cuneiform.",
answer: "D. cuneiform",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following leather articles was used for war and defence in the ancient days?",
A: "Apron",
B: "Vellum",
C: "Hassock",
D: "Quiver",
answer: "D. Quiver",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Identify the leather usually preferred for bookbinding.",
A: "Chamois",
B: "Nappa",
C: "Morocco",
D: "Suede",
answer: "C. Morocco",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Where should the keeper be on a belt?",
A: "At the tongue end",
B: "Behind the buckle",
C: "In the buckle",
D: "At the middle of the belt",
answer: "B. Behind the buckle",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The Brazillian hair sheepskin leather is termed",
A: "suede.",
B: "chamois.",
C: "cabretta.",
D: "cordovan.",
answer: "C. cabretta",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Chrome tanned leather is most suitable for",
A: "hand gloves.",
B: "shoe uppers.",
C: "fancy work.",
D: "sole leather.",
answer: "B. shoe uppers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of these attachments entails the use of a cap and a post?",
A: "Eyelets",
B: "Corners",
C: "Locks",
D: "Rebits",
answer: "A. Eyelets",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Identify the type of fibre of which synthetic leathers are composed.",
A: "Protein",
B: "Mineral",
C: "Vegetable",
D: "Cellulose",
answer: "D. Cellulose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following leathers lends itself for tooling?",
A: "Vegetable tanned",
B: "Alum tanned",
C: "Oil tanned",
D: "Chrome tanned",
answer: "A. Vegetable tanned",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Back straps are more convenient on",
A: "ladies bags.",
B: "shopping bags.",
C: "clutch bags.",
D: ",School bags.",
answer: "D. School bags",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A car manufacturer will need the services of",
A: "a saddler.",
B: "a tanner.",
C: "an upholsterer.",
D: "a cobbler.",
answer: "C. an upholsterer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A piece of leather suitable for creating articles should be",
A: "rough and stiff. °",
B: "smooth and flexible.",
C: "crumpled arid dyed.",
D: "buffed and toggled.",
answer: "B. smooth and flexible",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Most of the synthetic leather pieces are reinforced with",
A: "fabric.",
B: "cards.",
C: "rubber.",
D: "mesh.",
answer: "A. fabric",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following reasons is the most basic to be considered when making preliminary designs in leatherwork? It",
A: "helps to find market for the product.",
B: "provides the opportunity to know how to design well.",
C: "helps to cost leather articles:",
D: "helps to have the end product in view.",
answer: "D. helps to have the end product in view",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Tawing refers to the treatment of raw animal skin with",
A: "alum.",
B: "lime.",
C: "tannic solution.",
D: "acidic solution.",
answer: "A. alum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Cutting knives are best sharpened with",
A: "grease.",
B: "petrol.",
C: "kerosene.",
D: "oil.",
answer: "D. oil",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following are dyeing techniques in leather work?\nI Brush dyeing\nII Spray dyeing\nIII Hot dyeing\nIV Dip dyeing",
A: "I and III only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II; Il and IV only",
D: "I, Il and V_only",
answer: "D. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Identify the case for keeping knives from the following",
A: "shealth.",
B: "quiver.",
C: "holster.",
D: "scabboard.",
answer: "D. scabboard",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Another term for spirit-based dyes is",
A: "glaze.",
B: "liquor.",
C: "‘alkaline.",
D: "solvent.",
answer: "D. solvent",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Attaching a small piece of leather on a larger one of contrasting colours is termed",
A: "tooling.",
B: "quiltirig.,",
C: "embo§Ssment.",
D: "appliqué. ve",
answer: "D. appliqué",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following occurs naturally in skin?",
A: "Saliva °",
B: "Grease",
C: "Alkalies",
D: "Amino acid",
answer: "B. Grease",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A spacing wheel is suitable for",
A: "measuring stitch lines.",
B: "marking stitch holes.",
C: "piercing button spaces.",
D: "punching stitch holes.",
answer: "B. marking stitch holes",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Silk and synthetic threads are used to sew leather because they",
A: "are thin and long.",
B: "have elasticity that matches that of the leather.",
C: "have shinny surface that produce brilliant colours.",
D: "are colourful and can make sewing easy.",
answer: "B. have elasticity that matches that of the leather",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following woods is most appropriate for making a cutting board?",
A: "Odum",
B: "Wawa",
C: "Baobab",
D: "Teak",
answer: "D. Teak",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which one of the following leather articles fall under accessories?",
A: "Shoes",
B: "Belts",
C: "Coats",
D: "Gloves",
answer: "B. Belts",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Select the most appropriate substitute for a modeller.",
A: "Drive punch",
B: "Wooden mallet",
C: "Tracer",
D: "Deer foot",
answer: "C. Tracer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The property of leather which enables it to be shaped or modelled is known as",
A: "heat resistance.",
B: "thermal conductivity.",
C: "plasicity.",
D: "porosity.",
answer: "C. plasicity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Inserting and sewing a folded narrow strip of leather between two adjoining seams is termed",
A: "piping.",
B: "bating.",
C: "tacking.",
D: "cording.",
answer: "A. piping",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Cutting off excess leather-ends and threads is referred to as",
A: "dehairing.",
B: "skiving.",
C: "trimming.",
D: "shedding",
answer: "C. trimming",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following group of animals belong to the equine group?",
A: "Pig and peccary",
B: "Horse and ass",
C: "Seal and walrus",
D: "Cow and steer",
answer: "B. Horse and ass",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Identify the part labelled ACDF.",
A: "Butt",
B: "Belly",
C: "Double shoulder",
D: "Double bend",
answer: "A. Butt",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which part is labelled DFGI.",
A: "Butt",
B: "Belly",
C: "Single bend",
D: "Double bend Turn over",
answer: "C. Single bend",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. What is the part labelled FPQI?",
A: "Shank",
B: "Belly",
C: "Double bend",
D: "40.Double butt",
answer: "D. Double butt",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A crumpled leather is best straightened by moistening, stretching and",
A: "ironing it.",
B: "aerating it.",
C: "keeping under weight.",
D: "running a roller over it.",
answer: "A. ironing it",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Differentiate between Skivers and Skiving.",
A: "Skivers refer to type of leather, skiving is a cutting method.",
B: "Skivers refer to the tools while skiving describes a cutting method.",
C: "Skivers refer to strips of leather, skiving refers to a knife.",
D: "Skivers describes a type of tool, skiving refers to the use of the tool.",
answer: "A. Skivers refer to type of leather, skiving is a cutting method.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following stitches are similar?",
A: "Whip and overcast",
B: "Saddle and stem",
C: "Slanting and running",
D: "Cordovan and criss-cross",
answer: "B. Saddle and stem",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Aerating leather means",
A: "exposing it to air.",
B: "waxing it.",
C: "brushing it.",
D: "rubbing it with a rag.",
answer: "A. exposing it to air",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following tools has multi-purpose functions?",
A: "Drive punch",
B: "Oblong punch",
C: "Rotary punch",
D: "Combination punch",
answer: "D. Combination punch",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The first process of converting raw skin to leather is",
A: "flaying.",
B: "liming.",
C: "soaking.",
D: "shaving.",
answer: "A. flaying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following seams is best used for soles?",
A: "Recessed",
B: "Plain",
C: "Abutted",
D: "Fringed",
answer: "C. Abutted",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]